<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on DASH Industry Forum</title>
    <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on DASH Industry Forum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The DASH-IF hosts and manages an online cataloging of identifiers for MPEG-DASH profiles, interoperability points, content protection metadata and other DASH related specific schemes. DASH-IF responsibilities include:
 hosting the online catalog on its website, listing all defined URIs along with a short descriptions of their schemes and names of their owners, providing a simple online mechanism to request the addition of new URIs and associated information, and finally managing the administration and maintenance of the online catalog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/registration/</guid>
      <description>New identifiers can be registered at this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>In April 2012, ISO, the international standards body which had already given us the core media foundations of MPEG-2, MP3 and MP4, finally ratified the version of its next generation adaptive streaming standard: MPEG-DASH. In an industry besieged by three comparable (but incompatible) segmented formats many asked – why another? The participating companies in the MPEG-DASH standardization (including Microsoft, Apple, Netflix, Qualcomm, Ericsson, Samsung, and many others) saw a vision of interoperability and convergence required for large-scale market growth that trumped the proprietary and competing solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Completed DASH-IF Interoperability Documents Disclaimer The documents below are stable and have undergone a community review. However, the DASH-IF welcomes feedback on these published documents, e.g, request for clarifications or bugs. For this purpose, please use the Github bug tracker cited along with the documents.
DASH-IF Interoperability Points and Extensions Latest Version:
 Guidelines for Implementation: DASH-IF Interoperability Points V4.2: Multiple Clarifications and Bug fixes | (Bugtracker) | (diff to v4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/members/</guid>
      <description> Would you like to join? If so, find out about our membership levels, fees and IPR policy.
Charter Members         Contributor Members                                              Associate Members                               </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/</guid>
      <description>The MPEG-DASH standard has raised a huge momentum within both industry and academia. The DASH-IF provides – among others – interoperability guidelines and test vectors, and closes the gap enabling interoperable deployments. In recent years, we have seen a tremendous amount of research papers addressing various issues in and around DASH, and thus, the DASH-IF established an academic track to:
 identify research communities working in the area of DASH, create awareness of DASH-IF material and promote it within the academic community, and solicit research within and collect results from the academic community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>A number of reference and demonstration MPEG DASH players, player libraries and packagers are publicly available.
Reference client The first DASH IF Reference Player is written using Javascript. It works in any HTML5 browser which supports the MediaSource Extensions and Encrypted Media Extensions. The latest released player version as well as all archived player versions are mounted at https://reference.dashif.org/dash.js/
The framework source code is downloadable from our Github repository at https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clients</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/clients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/clients/</guid>
      <description>A wide variety of commercial client and player component software is already available for the playback of MPEG-DASH. This page details the client software available today from DASH Industry Forum members: Aricent, AvidBeam, bitdash, BuyDRM, castlabs, Digital Primates, InterDigital, NexStreaming, Qualcomm, RealNetworks, StreamOne and VisualOn. Opens-source client implementations, including dash.js, can be located in the Software tab above.
 Aricent has developed a feature-rich DASH Streaming player that supports the delivery of MPEG-DASH (Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description>February 22, 2017 The State of MPEG-DASH 2017, streamingmediaglobal.com
March 30, 2016 The State of MPEG-DASH 2016, streamingmedia.com
Dec 10th, 2015 DASH-IF Content Protection Information Exchange Format (CPIX) v2.0 open for Community Review
Sep 1st, 2015 DASH IF Interop Guidelines 3.2 released
July 8, 2015 Hulu’s Move to DASH, streamingmediaglobal.com
March 14, 2015 The State of MPEG-DASH 2015, streamingmedia.com
October 2, 2014 IBC Attendees Move in Unison to the Next Big Thing, streamingmedia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>The DASH-IF mailing address is:
3855 SW 153rd Dr.
Beaverton, OR 97003
USA
For general enquiries, please use this email address:
If you wish to send a formal liaison communication, then please contact our Liaison Officer William Frantz at</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/conformance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/conformance/</guid>
      <description>Available at https://conformance.dashif.org, the validator/conformance software validates DASH content (MPD and segments based on ISO-BMFF):
 The timing embedded in each representation is correct or not (segment index ‘sidx’, ‘tfdt’, …) Mandatory DASH parameters are properly encoded (SAP, fragment offsets,…). Cross-representation checks (Segment/subsegment alignment, bitstream switching). Whether there are missing segments.  The validation software was recently updated to allow validation against DASH IF, DVB, HbbTV and CMAF profiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/excellence-in-dash-award-acm-mmsys-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/excellence-in-dash-award-acm-mmsys-2016/</guid>
      <description>In conjunction with ACM MMSys 2016, being held in Klagenfurt Austria, the DASH Industry Forum is proud to announce the establishment of the
DASH Industry Forum Excellence in DASH Award
This award offers a financial prize for those papers which best meet the following requirements:
 Paper must substantially address MPEG DASH as the presentation format Paper must be selected for presentation at ACM MMSys 2016 Preference given to practical enhancements and developments which can sustain future commercial usefulness of DASH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/excellence-in-dash-award-acm-mmsys-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/excellence-in-dash-award-acm-mmsys-2017/</guid>
      <description>In conjunction with ACM MMSys 2017, being held in Taipei, Taiwan | June 20-23, 2017, the DASH Industry Forum is proud to announce the establishment of the
DASH Industry Forum Excellence in DASH Award
This award offers a financial prize for those papers which best meet the following requirements:
 Paper must substantially address MPEG DASH as the presentation format Paper must be selected for presentation at ACM MMSys 2017 Preference given to practical enhancements and developments which can sustain future commercial usefulness of DASH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/icme2017grandchallenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/icme2017grandchallenge/</guid>
      <description>Host organization: DASH-IF (https://dashif.org/)
Coordinator Contacts: Christian Timmerer, Chair of DASH-IF Academic Track (christian.timmerer@itec.aau.at) Ali C. Begen (ali.begen@networked.media)
DASH-IF Grand Challenge: Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP Challenge Description Real-time entertainment services such as streaming video and audio are currently accounting for more than 70% of the Internet traffic during peak hours. Interestingly, these services are all delivered over-the-top (OTT) of the existing networking infrastructure using the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/ipr-declarations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/ipr-declarations/</guid>
      <description>DASH-IF has been facilitating and promoting the adoption of the MPEG-DASH standard fsince 2012 and is known by the industry as the authority on the DASH standard and its deployment. DASH-IF believes that the DASH standard enables the industry to create an open, interoperable, multi-vendor ecosystem for the internet video streaming market, and is committed to industry-wide deployment of the MPEG-DASH standard. To help further accelerate the market adoption of MPEG-DASH, some of our member companies who are major contributors to the MPEG-DASH standard have made announcements regarding access to their essential DASH patents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/membership/</guid>
      <description>Membership in DASH-IF offers some great benefits. We have three membership levels and the benefits of each are included below:
Associate Membership Agreement
 Eligibility to participate in Working Groups  Interoperability Working Group Promotion Working Group  Opportunities to participate in DASH-IF marketing programs and events Discounts on promotional activities such as interoperability workshops Ability to provide feedback on certain draft deliverables Early access to Test Vectors, Test Tools, and Guidelines  Contributor Membership Agreement</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Source Metadata</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/audio_source_metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/audio_source_metadata/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Audio source data may be used in order to provide details of the audio content source. In general, such characteristics of audio are logically independent of the compression format. In the context of DASH they are typically used in order to select a proper Adaptation Set. This section focuses on source format description.
In the context of DASH as specific source descriptor exists, namely AudioConfiguration identifies channel configuration signaling for Representations that contain an audio component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication and Authorization</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/authentication_and_authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/authentication_and_authorization/</guid>
      <description> Introduction Authentication and authorization may be provided in the MPD.
Authentication Schemes The following defines a set of URIs that identify MPD events, i.e., schemes contained in the EventStream element:
   Identifier Reference Abstract     urn: see Authentication    Authorization Schemes The following defines a set of URIs that identify MPD events, i.e., schemes contained in the EventStream element:
   Identifier Reference Abstract     urn: see Authorization    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Protection</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_protection/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For the element ContentProtection the @schemeIdUri attribute is used to identify a content protection scheme (for details see ISO/IEC 23009-1 [1], section 5.8.4.1). This attribute provide sufficient information, possibly in conjunction with the @value and/or extension attributes and elements, such as the DRM system(s), encryption algorithm(s), and key distribution scheme(s) employed, to enable a client to determine whether it can possibly play the protected content.
For Representations based on ISO/IEC 14496-12 [6] a content protection scheme using the Protection System Specific Header Box defined in ISO/IEC 23001-7 may be identified in the ContentProtection element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Rating</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_rating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_rating/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Content Rating may be provided in the MPD.
Content Rating Schemes The following defines a set of URIs that identify MPD events, i.e., schemes contained in the EventStream element:
   Identifier Reference Abstract     urn:dvb:iptv:guidance:2014 ETSI TS 103 285, clause 9.1.2.3 “urn:dvb:iptv:guidance:2014” where the id is either:‘G’ indicating that guidance text relating to the content is provided in the ExplanatoryText element within the ParentalGuidance element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Schemes</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/event_schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/event_schemes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Events may be provided in the MPD or within a Representation in order to signal aperiodic information to the DASH client or to an application. Events are timed, i.e. each event starts at a specific media presentation time and typically has a duration. To classify events a proper scheme identifier identifies the application such that the DASH client can forward the event to the proper application.
Two ways of signalling events are provided, namely</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functionality</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/functionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/functionality/</guid>
      <description>Functionality    Identifier Reference Abstract     https://dashif.org/guidelines/trickmode DASH-IF IOP v3.2, clause 3.2.9 Defines a trick mode Adaptation Set. If an Adaptation Set in annotated with the EssentialProperty descriptor with URI “https://dashif.org/guidelines/trickmode” then the DASH client shall not select any of the contained Representations for regular playout.   https://dashif.org/guidelines/AdaptationSetSwitching DASH-IF IOP v3.2, clause 3.8 Defines signaling that switching from one Adaptation Set to another Adaptation Set may be possible in a seamless manner from a content and timeline perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiles</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/profiles/</guid>
      <description>General MPEG DASH defines formats for MPDs and segments. In addition MPEG provides the ability to further restrict the applied formats by the definition of Profiles as defined on section 8 of ISO/IEC 23009-1 [1]. Profiles of DASH are defined to enable interoperability and the signaling of the use of features. Profiles are signaled in the @profiles parameter which may be present on different levels of the MPD.
Such a profile can also be understood as permission for DASH clients that implement the features required by the profile to process the Media Presentation (MPD document and Segments).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/references/</guid>
      <description>References [1] ISO/IEC 23009-1:2012, Information technology — Dynamic adaptive streaming over HTTP (DASH) — Part 1: Media presentation description and segment formats, Cor.1 (available as w13495)
[2] 3GPP TS26.247, Transparent end-to-end Packet-switched Streaming Service (PSS); Progressive Download and Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP (3GP-DASH), available at http://www.3gpp.org
[3] DASH-IF Guidelines for Implementation: DASH264/AVC Interoperability Points, v2.0, Aug. 2013
[4] ISO/IEC 23001-8, Information technology – MPEG systems technologies –– Part 8: Coding-independent code points</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting Schemes</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/reporting_schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/reporting_schemes/</guid>
      <description> Introduction Reporting scheme may be provided in the MPD.
Reporting Schemes    Identifier Reference Abstract     urn:dvb:dash:reporting:2014 ETSI TS 103 285, clause 10.12.3 The DVB Metric reporting mechanism defined by TS 103 285.   urn:3GPP:ns:PSS:DASH:QM10 3GPP TS 26.247, clause 10.5 This section specifies a 3GP-DASH quality reporting scheme. The quality reporting scheme is signaled using in the Reporting element in the Metrics element. The URN to be used for the Reporting@schemeIdUri shall be “urn:3GPP:ns:PSS:DASH:QM10”    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subtitle and Closed Captioning</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/subtitle_and_closed_captioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/subtitle_and_closed_captioning/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Beyond regular audio and video support, TV programs typically also require support for auxiliary components such as subtitles and closed captioning, often due to regulatory requirements. DASH-IF IOP provides tools to addresses these requirements. We collect them here.
Identifiers Signalling for the closed caption services is provided by including Accessibility descriptors. The Accessibility descriptor is included for the AdaptationSet and all included Representations shall provide equivalent captions. The @value attribute of each descriptor can be either list of languages or a complete map of services (or CC channels, in CEA-608 terminology).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Source Metadata</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/video_source_metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/video_source_metadata/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Video source data may be used in order to provide details of the video content source. In general, such characteristics of video are logically independent of the compression format. In the context of DASH they are typically used in order to select a proper Adaptation Set. This section focuses on source format description.
In the context of DASH as specific source descriptor exists, namely FramePacking used to identify the frame-packing configuration scheme employed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>