<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on DASH Industry Forum</title>
    <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on DASH Industry Forum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The DASH-IF hosts and manages an online cataloging of identifiers for MPEG-DASH profiles, interoperability points, content protection metadata and other DASH related specific schemes. DASH-IF responsibilities include:
 hosting the online catalog on its website, listing all defined URIs along with a short descriptions of their schemes and names of their owners, providing a simple online mechanism to request the addition of new URIs and associated information, and finally managing the administration and maintenance of the online catalog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/registration/</guid>
      <description>New identifiers can be registered at this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>In April 2012, ISO, the international standards body which had already given us the core media foundations of MPEG-2, MP3 and MP4, finally ratified the version of its next generation adaptive streaming standard: MPEG-DASH. In an industry besieged by three comparable (but incompatible) segmented formats many asked – why another? The participating companies in the MPEG-DASH standardization (including Microsoft, Apple, Netflix, Qualcomm, Ericsson, Samsung, and many others) saw a vision of interoperability and convergence required for large-scale market growth that trumped the proprietary and competing solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Introduction DASH-IF publishes primarily three types of documents:
 Completed Specifications and Guidelines: The documents below are stable and have undergone a community review. Documents for community review: These documents are technically solid, but public is asked for comments in order to improve details. Position and White Papers: These documents provide background and initial studies  Completed DASH-IF Interoperability Documents Disclaimer The documents below are stable and have undergone a community review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/members/</guid>
      <description> Would you like to join? If so, find out about our membership levels, fees and IPR policy.
Charter Members            Contributor Members                               Associate Members                          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/</guid>
      <description>The MPEG-DASH standard has raised a huge momentum within both industry and academia. The DASH-IF provides – among others – interoperability guidelines and test vectors, and closes the gap enabling interoperable deployments. In recent years, we have seen a tremendous amount of research papers addressing various issues in and around DASH, and thus, the DASH-IF established an academic track to:
 identify research communities working in the area of DASH, create awareness of DASH-IF material and promote it within the academic community, and solicit research within and collect results from the academic community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>A number of reference and demonstration MPEG DASH players, player libraries and packagers are publicly available.
Reference client The first DASH IF Reference Player is written using Javascript. It works in any HTML5 browser which supports the MediaSource Extensions and Encrypted Media Extensions. The latest released player version as well as all archived player versions are mounted at https://reference.dashif.org/dash.js/
The framework source code is downloadable from our Github repository at https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clients</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/clients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/clients/</guid>
      <description>A wide variety of commercial client and player component software is already available for the playback of MPEG-DASH. This page details the client software available today from DASH Industry Forum members: Aricent, AvidBeam, bitdash, BuyDRM, castlabs, Digital Primates, InterDigital, NexStreaming, Qualcomm, RealNetworks, StreamOne, Viaccess-Orca and VisualOn. Opens-source client implementations, including dash.js, can be located in the Software tab above.
 Aricent has developed a feature-rich DASH Streaming player that supports the delivery of MPEG-DASH (Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description>October 6, 2020 &amp;ndash; DASH-IF publishes a series of updates and extensions for the next IOP version and CPIX.
September 11, 2020 &amp;ndash; DASH-IF receives first hand information on Versatile Video Coding (VVC) from Dr. Ye-Kui Wang (ByteDance) during our virtual special sessions.
September 1, 2020 &amp;ndash; Our esteemed colleague Mike Dolan (Pearl TV) provides an article in the ATSC News: DASH INDUSTRY FORUM CONTINUES TO FORGE ADOPTION WITH ATSC 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>The DASH-IF mailing address is:
3855 SW 153rd Dr.
Beaverton, OR 97003
USA
For general enquiries, please use this email address:
admin@dashif.org
If you wish to send a formal liaison communication, then please contact our Liaison Officer Phillip Maness at
liaison@dashif.org</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/excellence-in-dash-award-acm-mmsys-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/excellence-in-dash-award-acm-mmsys-2016/</guid>
      <description>In conjunction with ACM MMSys 2016, being held in Klagenfurt Austria, the DASH Industry Forum is proud to announce the establishment of the
DASH Industry Forum Excellence in DASH Award
This award offers a financial prize for those papers which best meet the following requirements:
 Paper must substantially address MPEG DASH as the presentation format Paper must be selected for presentation at ACM MMSys 2016 Preference given to practical enhancements and developments which can sustain future commercial usefulness of DASH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/excellence-in-dash-award-acm-mmsys-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/excellence-in-dash-award-acm-mmsys-2017/</guid>
      <description>In conjunction with ACM MMSys 2017, being held in Taipei, Taiwan | June 20-23, 2017, the DASH Industry Forum is proud to announce the establishment of the
DASH Industry Forum Excellence in DASH Award
This award offers a financial prize for those papers which best meet the following requirements:
 Paper must substantially address MPEG DASH as the presentation format Paper must be selected for presentation at ACM MMSys 2017 Preference given to practical enhancements and developments which can sustain future commercial usefulness of DASH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/icme2017grandchallenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/icme2017grandchallenge/</guid>
      <description>Host organization: DASH-IF (https://dashif.org/)
Coordinator Contacts: Christian Timmerer, Chair of DASH-IF Academic Track (christian.timmerer@itec.aau.at) Ali C. Begen (ali.begen@networked.media)
DASH-IF Grand Challenge: Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP Challenge Description Real-time entertainment services such as streaming video and audio are currently accounting for more than 70% of the Internet traffic during peak hours. Interestingly, these services are all delivered over-the-top (OTT) of the existing networking infrastructure using the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/conformance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/conformance/</guid>
      <description>Available at https://conformance.dashif.org, the validator/conformance software validates DASH content (MPD and segments based on ISO-BMFF):
 The timing embedded in each representation is correct or not (segment index ‘sidx’, ‘tfdt’, …) Mandatory DASH parameters are properly encoded (SAP, fragment offsets,…). Cross-representation checks (Segment/subsegment alignment, bitstream switching). Whether there are missing segments.  The validation software was recently updated to allow validation against DASH IF, DVB, HbbTV and CMAF profiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/ipr-declarations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/ipr-declarations/</guid>
      <description>License declarations The DASH Industry Forum adheres to the terms of the Common Patent Policy for ITU-T/ ITU-R/ISOII EC and the Guidelines for Implementing the Common Patent Policy for ITU-TIITU-RIISO/IEC. Under these terms, all DASH IF work products are subject to a review phase before release. During this review period, member companies must declare if they hold any intellectual property that reads against the work item and the terms under which they will license this intellectual property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/membership/</guid>
      <description>Membership in DASH-IF offers some great benefits. We have three membership levels and the benefits of each are included below:
Associate Membership Agreement
 Eligibility to participate in Working Groups  Interoperability Working Group Promotion Working Group  Opportunities to participate in DASH-IF marketing programs and events Discounts on promotional activities such as interoperability workshops Ability to provide feedback on certain draft deliverables Early access to Test Vectors, Test Tools, and Guidelines  Contributor Membership Agreement</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/5g-workshop-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/5g-workshop-2018/</guid>
      <description>Video meets mobile -The 5G Opportunity Public Workshop co-sponsored by DASH-IF
August 20, 2015 - San Diego, CA, United States
Along with its 11th face to face meeting on August 18-20 in San Diego, the DASH Industry Forum (DASH-IF) used this opportunity to organize a workshop in order to gather experts from video distribution services, mobile operators and technology providers. With 5G on the horizon, this is an opportunity to understand some of the technical and non-technical challenges and opportunities for mobile video services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/award-will-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/award-will-law/</guid>
      <description>In conjunction with the Networking Reception held during IBC 2019 in Amsterdam, the DASH Industry Forum is proud to announce that the
DASH Industry Forum Leadership Award
is presented to
Will Law
for continuous leadership, promotion and technical contributions for the success of DASH.
Will Law from Akamai served and is serving DASH-IF in different roles since its inauguration in 2012. Among others, Will was leading the DASH-IF Promotion Working Group, acted as Vice President and President, and is leading the dash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/dvb-world-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/dvb-world-2020/</guid>
      <description>DVB World 2020: Joint DVB/DASH-IF Webinar is now online 
DASH-IF is proud and delighted having been part of a series of public and free webinars organized by Digital Video Broadcasting (DVB) project. The webinars replace DVB&amp;rsquo;s annual flagship conference DVB World in March 2020 that was cancelled due to the COVID-19 situation.
On March 31, 2020 at 4pm cest, the webinar DASH: from on-demand to large scale live for premium services was delivered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/live-media-ingest-specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/live-media-ingest-specification/</guid>
      <description>DASH-IF Publishes Live Media Ingest Technical Specification 
With 18 months of collaborative work, the DASH-IF published a technical specification on live media ingest. While DASH is excellent for streaming to clients, transmitting content from a live source to an origin or packager benefits from a different approach. The live media ingest specification provides this and defines a protocol to ingest DASH and CMAF content using the HTTP POST method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/low-latency-dash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/low-latency-dash/</guid>
      <description>DASH-IF publishes Low-Latency DASH extensions and 2nd Community Review for DASH-IF Ad Insertion Low-Latency DASH Modes 
Based on a report developed jointly between DVB and DASH-IF in 2017 on Low-Latency DASH, DASH-IF developed over the last 2 years detailed requirements and recommendations for service offerings and client implementation to support consistent latency in DASH for linear TV services. The change request builds on joint work in MPEG, DASH-IF and DVB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/speke-cpix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/speke-cpix/</guid>
      <description>DASH-IF publishes CPIX v2.3 for community review to address alignment between SPEKE and CPIX based on broad industry support 
DASH-IF&amp;rsquo;s CPIX 2.0 was published in September 2016. In November 2017, AWS Elemental released the first version of SPEKE, which is both a CPIX 2.0 profile, an API specification to transport CPIX documents and a set of deployment guidelines (for Content Key Encryption) – working with both on-premises equipment and cloud environments (AWS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/v5-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/v5-updates/</guid>
      <description>DASH-IF publishes a series of updates for next version of IOP Guidelines and for CPIX Background DASH-IF recently published the following new documents:
 Advanced Ad Insertion in DASH DASH events and timed metadata tracks timing and processing model and client reference model Audio Amendment to Guidelines for Implementation: DASH-IF Interoperability Points, Version 4.3 DASH-IF implementation guidelines: content protection and security DASH-IF Implementation Guidelines v2.3: Content Protection Information Exchange Format (CPIX)  The former four documents will be rolled into a new version of the DASH-IF IOP guidelines version 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/vvc-yk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/vvc-yk/</guid>
      <description>DASH-IF receives first hand information on Versatile Video Coding &amp;ndash; September 11, 2020 - Elbonia, virtual &amp;ndash;
Today, as part of our virtual special session series, DASH-IF received a primer on &amp;ldquo;The high-level syntax (HLS) designs in VVC&amp;rdquo; from Dr. Ye-Kui Wang, Principal Scientist at Bytedance. During session also colleagues from our partner organizations DVB, 3GPP and CTA WAVE were invited and many joined. We had an audience of 60 people, thanks everyone for joining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/workshop-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/workshop-2019/</guid>
      <description>DASH IF Workshop on Media Streaming Meets 5G Public Workshop co-sponsored by DASH-IF
Dec 9-10, 2019 - Portland, OR, USA
MISSION AND GOAL Along with its 21st face to face meeting on December 10-12 in Portland, OR, the DASH Industry Forum (DASH-IF) gathered experts from video distribution services, mobile operators and technology providers in order to look into 5G and Media Streaming. Around 50 experts joined and made the conference interactive and full of lively discussions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Source Metadata</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/audio_source_metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/audio_source_metadata/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Audio source data may be used in order to provide details of the audio content source. In general, such characteristics of audio are logically independent of the compression format. In the context of DASH they are typically used in order to select a proper Adaptation Set. This section focuses on source format description.
In the context of DASH as specific source descriptor exists, namely AudioConfiguration identifies channel configuration signaling for Representations that contain an audio component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication and Authorization</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/authentication_and_authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/authentication_and_authorization/</guid>
      <description> Introduction Authentication and authorization may be provided in the MPD.
Authentication Schemes The following defines a set of URIs that identify MPD events, i.e., schemes contained in the EventStream element:
   Identifier Reference Abstract     urn: see Authentication    Authorization Schemes The following defines a set of URIs that identify MPD events, i.e., schemes contained in the EventStream element:
   Identifier Reference Abstract     urn: see Authorization    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Protection</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_protection/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For the element ContentProtection the @schemeIdUri attribute is used to identify a content protection scheme (for details see ISO/IEC 23009-1 [1], section 5.8.4.1). This attribute provide sufficient information, possibly in conjunction with the @value and/or extension attributes and elements, such as the DRM system(s), encryption algorithm(s), and key distribution scheme(s) employed, to enable a client to determine whether it can possibly play the protected content.
For Representations based on ISO/IEC 14496-12 [6] a content protection scheme using the Protection System Specific Header Box defined in ISO/IEC 23001-7 may be identified in the ContentProtection element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Rating</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_rating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_rating/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Content Rating may be provided in the MPD.
Content Rating Schemes The following defines a set of URIs that identify MPD events, i.e., schemes contained in the EventStream element:
   Identifier Reference Section Comment     urn:dvb:iptv:guidance:2014 ETSI TS 103 285 clause 9.1.2.3 Where the id is either: G indicating that guidance text relating to the content is provided in the ExplanatoryText element within the ParentalGuidance element or W indicating watershed (safe harbour) content that is only suitable for presentation after the watershed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Schemes</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/event_schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/event_schemes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Events may be provided in the MPD or within a Representation in order to signal aperiodic information to the DASH client or to an application. Events are timed, i.e. each event starts at a specific media presentation time and typically has a duration. To classify events a proper scheme identifier identifies the application such that the DASH client can forward the event to the proper application.
Two ways of signalling events are provided, namely</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functionality</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/functionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/functionality/</guid>
      <description>Functionality    Identifier Reference Section Comment     https://dashif.org/guidelines/trickmode DASH-IF IOP v3.2 clause 3.2.9 Defines a trick mode Adaptation Set. If an Adaptation Set in annotated with the EssentialProperty descriptor with URI https://dashif.org/guidelines/trickmode then the DASH client shall not select any of the contained Representations for regular playout.   https://dashif.org/guidelines/AdaptationSetSwitching DASH-IF IOP v3.2 clause 3.8 Defines signaling that switching from one Adaptation Set to another Adaptation Set may be possible in a seamless manner from a content and timeline perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Output Protection</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/output_protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/output_protection/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Output protection schemes, such as HDCP are frequently used to protect the rendered output in transit from the decoding device to the displaying device (for example, from a set-top box which is connected to a TV set using an HDMI cable). These output protection schemes and their properties are frequently a pre-requisite for the ability to present the associated Representations.
For the element OutputProtection the @schemeIdUri attribute is used to identify an output protection scheme (for details see ISO/IEC 23009-1 [1], section 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiles</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/profiles/</guid>
      <description>General MPEG DASH defines formats for MPDs and segments. In addition MPEG provides the ability to further restrict the applied formats by the definition of Profiles as defined on section 8 of ISO/IEC 23009-1 [1]. Profiles of DASH are defined to enable interoperability and the signaling of the use of features. Profiles are signaled in the @profiles parameter which may be present on different levels of the MPD.
Such a profile can also be understood as permission for DASH clients that implement the features required by the profile to process the Media Presentation (MPD document and Segments).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/references/</guid>
      <description>References [1] ISO/IEC 23009-1:2019/DAmd.1:2020, Information technology — Dynamic adaptive streaming over HTTP (DASH) — Part 1: Media presentation description and segment formats, (available in MPEG w19282)
[2] 3GPP TS26.247, Transparent end-to-end Packet-switched Streaming Service (PSS); Progressive Download and Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP (3GP-DASH), available at http://www.3gpp.org
[3] DASH-IF Guidelines for Implementation: DASH264/AVC Interoperability Points, v2.0, Aug. 2013
[4] ISO/IEC 23001-8, Information technology – MPEG systems technologies –– Part 8: Coding-independent code points</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting Schemes</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/reporting_schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/reporting_schemes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Reporting scheme may be provided in the MPD.
Reporting Schemes    Identifier Reference Section Comment     urn:dvb:dash:reporting:2014 ETSI TS 103 285 clause 10.12.3 The DVB Metric reporting mechanism defined by TS 103 285.   urn:3GPP:ns:PSS:DASH:QM10 3GPP TS 26.247 clause 10.5 This section specifies a 3GP-DASH quality reporting scheme. The quality reporting scheme is signaled using in the Reporting element in the Metrics element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAND</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/sand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/sand/</guid>
      <description>General MPEG DASH part 5 Server And Network-assisted DASH defines messages and MPD signalling for a DASH client and a DANE (network entity) to exchange such SAND messages.
Test vectors for SAND MPDs and messages can be fond at Test Vectors.
The following are the identifiers defined in several specification related to SAND.
SAND    Identifier Reference Section Comment     http://dashif.org/guidelines/sand/modes/qoe DASH-IF SAND Interoperability 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subtitle and Closed Captioning</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/subtitle_and_closed_captioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/subtitle_and_closed_captioning/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Beyond regular audio and video support, TV programs typically also require support for auxiliary components such as subtitles and closed captioning, often due to regulatory requirements. DASH-IF IOP provides tools to addresses these requirements. We collect them here.
Identifiers Signalling for the closed caption services is provided by including Accessibility descriptors. The Accessibility descriptor is included for the AdaptationSet and all included Representations shall provide equivalent captions. The @value attribute of each descriptor can be either list of languages or a complete map of services (or CC channels, in CEA-608 terminology).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Source Metadata</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/video_source_metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/video_source_metadata/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Video source data may be used in order to provide details of the video content source. In general, such characteristics of video are logically independent of the compression format. In the context of DASH they are typically used in order to select a proper Adaptation Set. This section focuses on source format description.
In the context of DASH as specific source descriptor exists, namely FramePacking used to identify the frame-packing configuration scheme employed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>