<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on DASH Industry Forum</title>
    <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on DASH Industry Forum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/icme2017grandchallenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/icme2017grandchallenge/</guid>
      <description>Host organization: DASH-IF (https://dashif.org/)
Coordinator Contacts: Christian Timmerer, Chair of DASH-IF Academic Track (christian.timmerer@itec.aau.at) Ali C. Begen (ali.begen@networked.media)
DASH-IF Grand Challenge: Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP Challenge Description Real-time entertainment services such as streaming video and audio are currently accounting for more than 70% of the Internet traffic during peak hours. Interestingly, these services are all delivered over-the-top (OTT) of the existing networking infrastructure using the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/ipr-declarations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/ipr-declarations/</guid>
      <description>DASH-IF has been facilitating and promoting the adoption of the MPEG-DASH standard fsince 2012 and is known by the industry as the authority on the DASH standard and its deployment. DASH-IF believes that the DASH standard enables the industry to create an open, interoperable, multi-vendor ecosystem for the internet video streaming market, and is committed to industry-wide deployment of the MPEG-DASH standard. To help further accelerate the market adoption of MPEG-DASH, some of our member companies who are major contributors to the MPEG-DASH standard have made announcements regarding access to their essential DASH patents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/membership/</guid>
      <description>Membership in DASH-IF offers some great benefits. We have three membership levels and the benefits of each are included below:
Associate Membership Agreement
 Eligibility to participate in Working Groups  Interoperability Working Group Promotion Working Group  Opportunities to participate in DASH-IF marketing programs and events Discounts on promotional activities such as interoperability workshops Ability to provide feedback on certain draft deliverables Early access to Test Vectors, Test Tools, and Guidelines  Contributor Membership Agreement</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>In April 2012, ISO, the international standards body which had already given us the core media foundations of MPEG-2, MP3 and MP4, finally ratified the version of its next generation adaptive streaming standard: MPEG-DASH. In an industry besieged by three comparable (but incompatible) segmented formats many asked – why another? The participating companies in the MPEG-DASH standardization (including Microsoft, Apple, Netflix, Qualcomm, Ericsson, Samsung, and many others) saw a vision of interoperability and convergence required for large-scale market growth that trumped the proprietary and competing solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/</guid>
      <description>The MPEG-DASH standard has raised a huge momentum within both industry and academia. The DASH-IF provides – among others – interoperability guidelines and test vectors, and closes the gap enabling interoperable deployments. In recent years, we have seen a tremendous amount of research papers addressing various issues in and around DASH, and thus, the DASH-IF established an academic track to:
 identify research communities working in the area of DASH, create awareness of DASH-IF material and promote it within the academic community, and solicit research within and collect results from the academic community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clients</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/clients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/clients/</guid>
      <description>A wide variety of commercial client and player component software is already available for the playback of MPEG-DASH. This page details the client software available today from DASH Industry Forum members: Aricent, AvidBeam, bitdash, BuyDRM, castlabs, Digital Primates, InterDigital, NexStreaming, Qualcomm, RealNetworks, StreamOne and VisualOn. Opens-source client implementations, including dash.js, can be located in the Software tab above.
 Aricent has developed a feature-rich DASH Streaming player that supports the delivery of MPEG-DASH (Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>The DASH-IF mailing address is:
3855 SW 153rd Dr.
Beaverton, OR 97003
USA
For general enquiries, please use this email address:
If you wish to send a formal liaison communication, then please contact our Liaison Officer William Frantz at</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Completed DASH-IF Interoperability Documents Disclaimer The documents below are stable and have undergone a community review. However, the DASH-IF welcomes feedback on these published documents, e.g, request for clarifications or bugs. For this purpose, please use the Github bug tracker cited along with the documents.
DASH-IF Interoperability Points and Extensions Latest Version:
 Guidelines for Implementation: DASH-IF Interoperability Points V4.2: Multiple Clarifications and Bug fixes | (Bugtracker) | (diff to v4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifiers</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/members/</guid>
      <description> Would you like to join? If so, find out about our membership levels, fees and IPR policy.
Charter Members         Contributor Members                                              Associate Members                              </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description>February 22, 2017 The State of MPEG-DASH 2017, streamingmediaglobal.com
March 30, 2016 The State of MPEG-DASH 2016, streamingmedia.com
Dec 10th, 2015 DASH-IF Content Protection Information Exchange Format (CPIX) v2.0 open for Community Review
Sep 1st, 2015 DASH IF Interop Guidelines 3.2 released
July 8, 2015 Hulu’s Move to DASH, streamingmediaglobal.com
March 14, 2015 The State of MPEG-DASH 2015, streamingmedia.com
October 2, 2014 IBC Attendees Move in Unison to the Next Big Thing, streamingmedia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>A number of reference and demonstration MPEG DASH players, player libraries and packagers are publicly available.
Reference client The first DASH IF Reference Player is written using Javascript. It works in any HTML5 browser which supports the MediaSource Extensions and Encrypted Media Extensions. The latest released player version as well as all archived player versions are mounted at https://reference.dashif.org/dash.js/
The framework source code is downloadable from our Github repository at https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Assets</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/test_assets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/test_assets/</guid>
      <description>VOD The DASH Industry Forum maintains a publicly accessible and free-to-use repository of test assets. The repository is available at
 http://testassets.dashif.org/
 It is searchable via feature groups, features and test cases.

LIVE The DASH industry Fourm maintains a suite of 24&amp;frasl;7 available live streams for reference purposes. The streams are generated by our Live Simulator. Test URLs are available at
 https://github.com/Dash-Industry-Forum/dash-live-source-simulator/wiki/Test-URLs
 Instructions for how to configure the streams are available at</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>