<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on DASH Industry Forum</title>
    <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on DASH Industry Forum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>In April 2012, ISO, the international standards body which had already given us the core media foundations of MPEG-2, MP3 and MP4, finally ratified the version of its next generation adaptive streaming standard: MPEG-DASH. In an industry besieged by three comparable (but incompatible) segmented formats many asked – why another? The participating companies in the MPEG-DASH standardization (including Microsoft, Apple, Netflix, Qualcomm, Ericsson, Samsung, and many others) saw a vision of interoperability and convergence required for large-scale market growth that trumped the proprietary and competing solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/academic/</guid>
      <description>The MPEG-DASH standard has raised a huge momentum within both industry and academia. The DASH-IF provides – among others – interoperability guidelines and test vectors, and closes the gap enabling interoperable deployments. In recent years, we have seen a tremendous amount of research papers addressing various issues in and around DASH, and thus, the DASH-IF established an academic track to:
 identify research communities working in the area of DASH, create awareness of DASH-IF material and promote it within the academic community, and solicit research within and collect results from the academic community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clients</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/clients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/clients/</guid>
      <description>A wide variety of commercial client and player component software is already available for the playback of MPEG-DASH. This page details the client software available today from DASH Industry Forum members: Aricent, AvidBeam, bitdash, BuyDRM, castlabs, Digital Primates, InterDigital, NexStreaming, Qualcomm, RealNetworks, StreamOne and VisualOn. Opens-source client implementations, including dash.js, can be located in the Software tab above.
 Aricent has developed a feature-rich DASH Streaming player that supports the delivery of MPEG-DASH (Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>The DASH-IF mailing address is:
3855 SW 153rd Dr.
Beaverton, OR 97003
USA
For general enquiries, please use this email address:
If you wish to send a formal liaison communication, then please contact our Liaison Officer William Frantz at</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Completed DASH-IF Interoperability Documents Disclaimer The documents below are stable and have undergone a community review. However, the DASH-IF welcomes feedback on these published documents, e.g, request for clarifications or bugs. For this purpose, please use the Github bug tracker cited along with the documents.
DASH-IF Interoperability Points and Extensions Latest Version:
 Guidelines for Implementation: DASH-IF Interoperability Points V4.2: Multiple Clarifications and Bug fixes | (Bugtracker) | (diff to v4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifiers</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/members/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>A number of reference and demonstration MPEG DASH players, player libraries and packagers are publicly available.
Reference client The first DASH IF Reference Player is written using Javascript. It works in any HTML5 browser which supports the MediaSource Extensions and Encrypted Media Extensions. The latest released player version as well as all archived player versions are mounted at https://reference.dashif.org/dash.js/
The framework source code is downloadable from our Github repository at https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Assets</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/test_assets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/test_assets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>