<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on DASH Industry Forum</title>
    <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on DASH Industry Forum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/live-media-ingest-specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/live-media-ingest-specification/</guid>
      <description>DASH-IF Publishes Live Media Ingest Technical Specification 
With 18 months of collaborative work, the DASH-IF published a technical specification on live media ingest. While DASH is excellent for streaming to clients, transmitting content from a live source to an origin or packager benefits from a different approach. The live media ingest specification provides this and defines a protocol to ingest DASH and CMAF content using the HTTP POST method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/low-latency-dash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/low-latency-dash/</guid>
      <description>DASH-IF publishes Low-Latency DASH extensions and 2nd Community Review for DASH-IF Ad Insertion Low-Latency DASH Modes 
Based on a report developed jointly between DVB and DASH-IF in 2017 on Low-Latency DASH, DASH-IF developed over the last 2 years detailed requirements and recommendations for service offerings and client implementation to support consistent latency in DASH for linear TV services. The change request builds on joint work in MPEG, DASH-IF and DVB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/speke-cpix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/news/speke-cpix/</guid>
      <description>DASH-IF publishes CPIX v2.3 for community review to address alignment between SPEKE and CPIX based on broad industry support 
DASH-IF&amp;rsquo;s CPIX 2.0 was published in September 2016. In November 2017, AWS Elemental released the first version of SPEKE, which is both a CPIX 2.0 profile, an API specification to transport CPIX documents and a set of deployment guidelines (for Content Key Encryption) – working with both on-premises equipment and cloud environments (AWS).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>