<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Identifiers on DASH Industry Forum</title>
    <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Identifiers on DASH Industry Forum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Protection</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_protection/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For the element ContentProtection the @schemeIdUri attribute is used to identify a content protection scheme (for details see ISO/IEC 23009-1 [1], section 5.8.4.1). This attribute provide sufficient information, possibly in conjunction with the @value and/or extension attributes and elements, such as the DRM system(s), encryption algorithm(s), and key distribution scheme(s) employed, to enable a client to determine whether it can possibly play the protected content.
For Representations based on ISO/IEC 14496-12 [6] a content protection scheme using the Protection System Specific Header Box defined in ISO/IEC 23001-7 may be identified in the ContentProtection element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Rating</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_rating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/content_rating/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Content Rating may be provided in the MPD.
Content Rating Schemes The following defines a set of URIs that identify MPD events, i.e., schemes contained in the EventStream element:
   Identifier Reference Abstract     urn:dvb:iptv:guidance:2014 ETSI TS 103 285, clause 9.1.2.3 “urn:dvb:iptv:guidance:2014” where the id is either:‘G’ indicating that guidance text relating to the content is provided in the ExplanatoryText element within the ParentalGuidance element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The DASH-IF hosts and manages an online cataloging of identifiers for MPEG-DASH profiles, interoperability points, content protection metadata and other DASH related specific schemes. DASH-IF responsibilities include:
 hosting the online catalog on its website, listing all defined URIs along with a short descriptions of their schemes and names of their owners, providing a simple online mechanism to request the addition of new URIs and associated information, and finally managing the administration and maintenance of the online catalog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiles</title>
      <link>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dash-industry-forum.github.io/identifiers/profiles/</guid>
      <description>General MPEG DASH defines formats for MPDs and segments. In addition MPEG provides the ability to further restrict the applied formats by the definition of Profiles as defined on section 8 of ISO/IEC 23009-1 [1]. Profiles of DASH are defined to enable interoperability and the signaling of the use of features. Profiles are signaled in the @profiles parameter which may be present on different levels of the MPD.
Such a profile can also be understood as permission for DASH clients that implement the features required by the profile to process the Media Presentation (MPD document and Segments).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>